Prepare for adventure. Count on revenge.
The Count of Monte Cristo is a adventure, drama,
history film directed by Kevin Reynolds.
Edmond Dantés's life and plans to marry the beautiful Mercedes are
shattered when his best friend, Fernand, deceives him.
After spending 13 miserable years in prison, Dantés escapes with the help of a fellow inmate
and plots his revenge, cleverly insinuating himself into the French nobility.
Edmond Dantes, played by Jim Caviezel.
Fernand Mondego, played by Guy Pearce.
Abbé Faria, played by Richard Harris.
J.F. Villefort, played by James Frain.
Mercedes Iguanada, played by Dagmara Dominczyk.
Armand Dorleac, played by Michael Wincott.
The Count of Monte Cristo is a 2002 historical adventure film, which is an adaptation of the 1844 novel of the same name by
Alexandre Dumas, produced by Roger Birnbaum, Gary Barber, and Jonathan Glickman, and directed by Kevin Reynolds.
The film stars Jim Caviezel, Guy Pearce, Richard Harris, James Frain, Dagmara
Dominczyk, Luis Guzmán and Henry Cavill in one of his earliest roles.
It follows the general plot of the novel, with the main storyline of imprisonment and revenge preserved, but
many elements, including the relationships between major characters and the ending were modified.
The Count of Monte Cristo was released in North America on January
25, 2002, to generally positive reviews from critics.
It was commercially successful, grossing $75 million.
The film explores themes of treasure, based on novel or book,
loss of loved one, marseille, france, female lover.
The tone is emotional and intense.